Katharine Kuh
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Katharine Kuh papers
1875-1994, bulk 1930-1994
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Kuh, Katharine
12.1 linear feet
The papers of art historian, dealer, critic, and curator Katharine Kuh measure 12.1 linear feet and date from 1875-1994, with the bulk of the material dating from 1930-1994. The collection documents Kuh's career as a pioneer modernist art historian and as the first woman curator of European Art and Sculpture at the Art Institute of Chicago. Found within the papers are biographical material; correspondence with family, friends and colleagues; personal business records; artwork by various artists; a travel journal; writings by Kuh and others; scrapbooks; printed material; photographs of Kuh and others; and audio recordings of Kuh's lectures and of Daniel Catton Rich reading poetry.
Provenance
The Katharine Kuh papers were donated in several installments from 1971 to 1989 by Katharine Kuh and in 1994 by her estate. Artwork was donated in 1995 by Kuh's former employer, the Art Institute of Chicago.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of this collection are available on 35mm microfilm reels 265, 267, 2225-2227, and 2288 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the collection as described in this finding aid may not reflect the order of the collection on microfilm.
Restrictions on Access
Authorization to quote, publish or reproduce requires written permission until 2019. Contact the Archives of American Art Reference Services department for additional information.
Biographical Note
Katharine Kuh (1904-1994) worked primarily in the Chicago area as an modern art historian, dealer, critic, curator, writer, and consultant. She operated the Katharine Kuh Gallery from 1935-1943 and was the first woman curator of European and Art and Sculpture at the Art Institute of Chicago.
Katharine Kuh (née Woolf) was born on July 15, 1904 in St. Louis, Missouri, the youngest of the three daughters of Olga Weiner and Morris Woolf, a silk importer. In 1909, the family moved to Chicago, Illinois. While traveling with her family in Europe in 1914, Katharine contracted polio, causing her to spend the next decade in a body brace. During this time of restricted movement, she developed an interest in art history through the collecting of old master prints.
After her recovery, Katharine Woolf attended Vassar College where one of her professors, Alfred Barr, encouraged her to study modern art. She graduated from Vassar in 1925 and received a master's degree in art history from the University of Chicago in 1929. Later that year, she moved to New York to pursue a Ph.D. in Renaissance and medieval art at New York University.
In 1930, Katharine Woolf returned to Chicago and married businessman George Kuh and began to teach art history courses in the suburbs of Chicago. After divorcing George Kuh in 1935, she opened the Katharine Kuh Gallery, the first gallery devoted to avant-garde art in Chicago. It was also the first gallery to exhibit photography and typographical design as art forms, and featured the work of Ansel Adams, Josef Albers, Alexander Calder, Wassily Kandinsky, Fernand Léger, and Man Ray, among others. From 1938 to1940, Kuh was the Visiting Professor of Art at the University School of Fine Arts, San Miguel, Mexico.
After the Katharine Kuh Gallery closed in 1943, Kuh was hired by museum director Daniel Catton Rich to fill a position in public relations at the Art Institute of Chicago. During the following years, Kuh edited the museum's Quarterly publication, took charge of the museum's Gallery of Interpretive Art, and began a long term relationship with Rich. In 1946, Kuh was sent on a special mission for the U. S. Office of Indian Affairs to make a detailed study of Native American totemic carvings in Alaska.
In 1949, Kuh persuaded Mr. and Mrs. Walter Arensberg of Los Angeles to exhibit their collection of modern art, creating the first post-war exhibition of modern art in Chicago. She published her first book Art Has Many Faces in 1951, and in the following year, she began writing art criticism for The Saturday Review. In 1954, Kuh was appointed the first woman curator of European Art and Sculpture at the Art Institute. She assembled the American contribution for the Venice Biennale in 1956 and during these years, Kuh helped acquire many of the works of modern art currently in the museum's collection.
A year following Daniel Catton Rich's 1958 resignation from the Art Institute of Chicago, Kuh also resigned and pursued a career in New York as an art collection advisor, most notably for the First National Bank of Chicago. In 1959, Kuh was made art critic for The Saturday Review, and she continued to publish books, including The Artist's Voice in 1962, Break-Up: The Core of Modern Art in 1965, and The Open Eye: In Pursuit of Art in 1971.
Katharine Kuh died on January 10, 1994 in New York City.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of art historian, dealer, critic, and curator Katharine Kuh measure 12.1 linear feet and date from 1875-1994, with the bulk of the material dating from 1930-1994. Found within the papers are biographical material; correspondence with family, friends and colleagues; personal business records; artwork by various artists; a travel journal; writings by Kuh and others; scrapbooks; printed material; photographs of Kuh and others; and audio recordings of Kuh's lectures and of Daniel Catton Rich reading poetry.
Biographical material consists of copies of Kuh's birth certificate, resumés, passports, award certificates, honorary diplomas, and address books listing information about several prominent artists and colleagues.
Four linear feet of correspondence offers excellent documentation of Kuh's interest in art history, her travels, her career at the Art Institute of Chicago, her work as a corporate art advisor, and as an author. There are letters from her mother Olga Woolf, friends, and colleagues. There is extensive correspondence with various staff members of the Art Institute of Chicago, the First National Bank of Chicago, and The Saturday Review. Also of interest are letters from artists and collectors, several of whom became life-long friends including Walter and Louise Arensberg, Cosmo Campoli, Serge Chermayeff, Richard Cox, Worden Day, Claire Falkenstein, Fred Friendly, Leon Golub, Joseph Goto, David Hare, Denise Brown Hare, Jean Hélion, Ray Johnson, Gyorgy and Juliet Kepes, Len Lye, Wallace Putnam, Kurt Seligmann, Shelby Shackelford, Hedda Sterne, and Clyfford Still. Many letters are illustrated with original artwork in various media.
There are also scattered letters from various artists and other prominent individuals including Josef Albers, George Biddle, Marcel Breuer, Joseph Cornell, Stuart Davis, Edwin Dickinson, Joseph Hirshhorn, Daniel Catton Rich, and Dorothea Tanning.
Personal business records include a list of artwork, Olga Woolf's will, inventories of Kuh's personal art collection, miscellaneous contracts and deeds of gift, receipts for the sale of artwork, files concerning business-related travel, and miscellaneous receipts.
Artwork in the collection represents a wide range of artist friends and media, such as drawings, watercolors, paintings, collages, and prints. Included are works by various artists including lithographs by David Hare and a watercolor set, Technics and Creativity, designed and autographed by Jasper Johns for the Museum of Modern Art, 1970.
Notes and writings include annotated engagement calendars, travel journals for Germany, a guest book for the Kuh Memorial gathering, and many writings and notes by Kuh for lectures and articles concerning art history topics. Of interest are minutes/notes from meetings for art festivals, conferences, and the "Conversations with Artists Program (1961). Also found are writings by others about Kuh and other art history topics.
Six scrapbooks contain clippings that document the height of Kuh's career as a gallery director and museum curator. Scrapbook 6 contains clippings about Fernand Léger, the subject of a retrospective exhibition at the Art Institute of Chicago in 1953.
Additional printed material includes clippings about Kuh and her interests, a comprehensive collection of clippings of Kuh's articles for The Saturday Review, exhibition announcements and catalogs, calendars of events, programs, brochures, books including Poems by Kuh as a child, and reproductions of artwork. Of particular interest are the early and exhibition catalogs from the Katharine Kuh Gallery, and rare catalogs for artists including Jean Arp, Alexander Calder, Marc Chagall, Jean Dubuffet, Marcel Duchamp, Stanley William Hayter, Hans Hofmann, Wassily Kandinsky, Paul Klee, Franz Kline, Le Corbusier, Ludwig Mies van der Rohe, and Pablo Picasso.
Photographs provide important documentation of the life and career of Katharine Kuh and are of Kuh, family members, friends, colleagues, events, residences, and artwork. Several of the photographs of Kuh were taken by Will Barnet and Marcel Breuer and there is a notable pair of photo booth portraits of Kuh and a young Ansel Adams. There are also group photographs showing Angelica Archipenko with Kuh; designer Klaus Grabe; painters José Chavez Morado and Pablo O'Higgins in San Miguel, Mexico; Kuh at the Venice Biennale with friends and colleagues including Peggy Guggenheim, Frances Perkins, Daniel Catton Rich, and Harry Winston; and "The Pre-Depressionists" including Lorser Feitelson, Robert Inverarity, Helen Lundeberg, Arthur Millier, Myron Chester Nutting, and Muriel Tyler Nutting.
Photographs of exhibition installations and openings include views of the Katharine Kuh Gallery; Fernand Léger, Man Ray, and László Moholy-Nagy at the Art Institute of Chicago; and Philip Guston, Jimmy Ernst, Seymour H. Knox, Franz Kline, Robert Motherwell, and Mark Rothko at the Albright-Knox Art Gallery in Buffalo, New York. There are also photographs depicting three men posing as Léger's "Three Musicians" and the visit of Queen Elizabeth II to the Art Institute of Chicago. There is a photograph by Peter Pollack of an elk skull used as a model by Georgia O'Keeffe.
Additional photographs of friends and colleagues include Ivan Albright, Alfred Barr, Alexander Calder, Marc Chagall, Willem De Kooning, Edwin Dickinson, Marcel Duchamp, Claire Falkenstein, Alberto Giacometti, poet Robert Graves with Len Lye, Philip Johnson, Gyorgy and Juliet Kepes, Carlos Mérida, José Orozco, Hasan Ozbekhan, Pablo Picasso, Carl Sandberg, Ben Shahn, Otto Spaeth, Hedda Sterne, Adlai Stevenson, Clyfford Still, Mark Tobey, and composer Victor Young.
Photographs of artwork include totem poles in Alaska; work by various artists including Claire Falkenstein, Paul Klee, and Hedda Sterne; and work donated to the Guggenheim Museum.
Four audio recordings on cassette are of Katharine Kuh's lectures, including one about assembling corporate collections, and of Daniel Catton Rich reading his own poetry. There is also a recording of the Second Annual Dialogue between Broadcasters and Museum Educators.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series. Undated correspondence, artwork, and photographs of individual artists are arranged alphabetically. Otherwise, each series is arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1945-1992 (Box 1; 16 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1908-1994 (Boxes 1-5, 13-14, OV 15; 4.0 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1941-1989 (Box 5; 19 folders)
Series 4: Artwork, 1931-1986 (Boxes 5, 13-14, OVs 15-23; 1.7 linear feet)
Series 5: Notes and Writings, 1914-1994 (Boxes 5-7; 1.7 linear feet)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1935-1953 (Box 7; 8 folders)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1916-1992 (Boxes 7-10, 13, OV 22; 3.0 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1875-1993 (Boxes 10-13; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 9: Audio Recordings, 1977 (Box 12; 1 folder)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Albright, Ivan, 1897-; Archipenko, Alexander, 1887-1964; Arp, Jean, 1887-1966; Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1902-; Calder, Alexander,1898-1976; Chagall, Marc, 1887-; Chavez Morado, José, 1909-2002; De Kooning, Willem, 1904-; Dickinson, Edwin Walter, 1891-; Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-; Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968; Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1926-; Ernst, Jimmy, 1920-1984; Falkenstein, Claire, 1908-; Feitelson, Lorser, 1898-1978; Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966; Grabe, Klaus; Graves, Robert; Guggenheim, Peggy, 1898-; Guston, Philip, 1913-; Hayter, Stanley William, 1901-1988; Hofmann, Hans, 1880-1966; Inverarity, Robert Bruce, 1909-; Kandinsky, Wassily, 1866-1944; Kepes, Gyorgy, 1906-2001; Kepes, Juliet; Klee, Paul, 1879-1940; Kline, Franz, 1910-1962; Knox, Seymour H., 1898-1990; Johnson, Philip, 1906-; Le Corbusier, 1887-1965; Léger, Fernand, 1881-1955; Lundeberg, Helen, 1908-; Lye, Len, 1901-1980; Mérida, Carlos, 1891-; Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig, 1886-1969; Millier, Arthur, 1893-; Moholy-Nagy, László, 1895-1946; Motherwell, Robert; Nutting, Muriel Leone Tyler, b. 1892; Nutting, Myron Chester, 1890-1972; Perkins, Frances; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; O'Higgins, Pablo, 1904-; Orozco, José Clemente, 1883-1949; Ozbekhan, Hasan, 1921-2007; Ray, Man, 1890-1976; Rich, Daniel Catton, 1904-1976; Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970; Sandberg, Carl; Seligmann, Kurt, 1900-1962; Shahn, Ben, 1898-1969; Spaeth, Otto, d. 1966; Sterne, Hedda, 1916-; Stevenson, Adlai E.$q(Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965; Still, Clyfford, 1904-; Tobey, Mark; Winston, Harry Lewis; Young, Victor; Albright-Knox Art Gallery; Art Institute of Chicago -- Faculty; Katharine Kuh Gallery (Chicago, Ill.); Biennale di Venezia
Subjects-Topical:
Art, Abstract --United States; Art, American; Art festivals; Art galleries, Commercial -- Illinois -- Chicago; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- United States; Authors -- Illinois -- Chicago; Women art critics -- New York (State) -- New York; Women art critics -- Illinois -- Chicago; Women art dealers -- New York (State) -- New York; Women art dealers -- Illinois -- Chicago; Women art historians -- Illinois -- Chicago; Women museum curators -- Illinois -- Chicago
Types of Materials:
Awards; Calendars; Collages; Drawings; Illustrated Letters; Lecture notes; Lectures; Lithographs; Minutes; Paintings; Photographs; Poetry; Prints; Resumes; Sales records; Scrapbooks; Travel journals; Watercolors; Wills; Sound recordings; Visitors' books
Names:
Albers, Josef; Arensberg, Louise S. (Louise Stevenson), 1879-1953; Arensberg, Walter, 1878-1954; Barnet, Will, 1911; Biddle, George, 1885-; Breuer, Marcel, 1902-; Campoli, Cosmo; Chermayeff, Serge, 1900-; Cornell, Joseph; Cox, Richard; Davis, Stuart, 1892-1964; Day, Worden, 1916-1986; Dickinson, Edwin Walter, 1891-; Falkenstein, Claire, 1908-; Friendly, Fred W.; Golub, Leon, 1922-2004; Goto, Joseph; Hare, David, 1917-; Hare, Denise Browne; Hélion, Jean, 1904-1987; Hirshhorn, Joseph; Johns, Jasper, 1930-; Johnson, Ray, 1927-; Kepes, Gyorgy, 1906-2001; Kepes, Juliet; Lye, Len, 1901-1980; Pollack, Peter, 1909-1978 -- photographer; Putnam, Wallace, 1899; Rich, Daniel Catton, 1904-1976; Seligmann, Kurt, 1900-1962; Shackelford, Shelby; Sterne, Hedda, 1916-; Still, Clyfford, 1904-; Tanning, Dorothea, 1910-; Woolf, Olga
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1945-1922, Series 1:; (Box 1; 16 folders)
  Biographical material consists of copies of Kuh's birth certificate, resumés, passports, award certificates, honorary diplomas, and address books listing information about several prominent artists and colleagues.
  - Copies of Birth Certificate, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Resumés, 1959-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Passports, 1953-1973, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Professional Achievement Award, University of Chicago Alumni Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Honorary Doctor of Fine Arts Diploma, Kansas City Art Institute, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Honorary Doctor of Arts Diploma and Program, Columbia College, Chicago, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - University of Chicago Emeritus Club Membership Certificate, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters Diploma, The Maryland Institute, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Doctor of fine Arts Diploma, University of Alaska, Anchorage, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ceremony of Recognition, Illinois Academy of Fine Arts (IAFA), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Address Books, 1965-1987, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-16)
- Correspondence, 1908-1994, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-5, 13-14, OV 15; 4.0 linear feet)
  Correspondence is between Kuh, her mother, friends, and colleagues and discuss her study of art history, her travels, her work at the Art Institute of Chicago, as a corporate art advisor, and as an author. Many letters are illustrated with original artwork including a card from Denise René containing a silkscreen print by Vasarely. There is extensive correspondence with staff of the Art Institute of Chicago, the First National Bank of Chicago, and The Saturday Review.
  Additional notable correspondents include Walter and Louise Arensberg, Cosmo Campoli, Serge Chermayeff, Richard Cox, Worden Day, Claire Falkenstein, Fred Friendly, Leon Golub, Joseph Goto, David Hare, Denise Brown Hare, Jean Hélion, Ray Johnson, Gyorgy and Juliet Kepes, Len Lye, Wallace Putnam, Kurt Seligmann, Shelby Shackelford, Hedda Sterne, Clyfford Still, and Kuh's mother, Olga Woolf.
  There are also scattered letters from Josef Albers, Ivan Albright, Saradell Ard, Elise Asher, Alfred Barr, George Biddle, Marcel Breuer, Joseph Cornell, Stuart Davis, Edwin Dickinson, Werner Drewes, Elsie Driggs, Jimmy Ernst, Philip Evergood, Lorser Feitelson, Joseph Friebert, Naum Gabo, Lee Gatch, John Davis Hatch, Clinton Hill, Joseph Hirshhorn, Hans Hofmann, Fernand Léger, Seymour Lipton, Carlos Mérida, Reuben Nakian, Isamu Noguchi, Philip Pavia, Daniel Catton Rich, Theodore Roszak, Dorothea Tanning, Lenore Tawney, Jack Tworkov, Dr. Vincent W. Van Gogh, Hugo Weber, Emerson Woelffer, and Robert Jay Wolff.
  - Correspondents With Unknown Surnames, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Correspondent Surnames "A," undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Correspondent Surnames "B," undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Correspondent Surnames "C," undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - Correspondent Surnames "D"-"E," undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondent Surnames "F," undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondent Surnames "G," undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondent Surnames "H," undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Correspondent Surnames "I"-"J," undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondent Surnames "K," undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letters from Gyorgy and Juliet Kepes, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letters from Katharine Kuh, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 33-36)
  - Correspondent Surnames "L," undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondent Surnames "M," undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondent Surnames "N"-"O," undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondent Surnames "P," undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondent Surnames "R," undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
  - Correspondent Surnames "S," undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-45)
  - Letters from Hedda Sterne, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondent Surnames "T," undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondent Surnames "V," undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondent Surnames "W"-"Y," undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1908-1924 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Letters from Katharine Woolf to Henry Friendly, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1946, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 56-57)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1949, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1951, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 62-63)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, 1960, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963, (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, 1964, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
  - Correspondence, 1965, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11-16)
  - Correspondence, 1966, (10 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-26)
  - Correspondence, 1967, (10 folders) (Box 2, Folder 27-36)
  - Correspondence, 1968, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 37-43)
  - Correspondence, 1969, (7 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 2, Folder 44-50)
  - Correspondence, 1970, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 51-57)
  - Correspondence, 1971, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 58-62)
  - Correspondence, 1972, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 63-66)
  - Correspondence, 1973, (7 folders; see also OV 15) (Box 2, Folder 67-73)
  - Correspondence, 1974, (7 folders; see also OV 15) (Box 2, Folder 74-80)
  - Correspondence, 1975, (6 folders; see also OV 15) (Box 2, Folder 81-86)
  - Correspondence, 1976, (8 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence, 1977, (7 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 3, Folder 9-15)
  - Correspondence, 1978, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 61-21)
  - Correspondence, 1979, (9 folders; see also Boxes 13-14) (Box 3, Folder 22-30)
  - Correspondence, 1980, (11 folders; see also Box 14) (Box 3, Folder 31-41)
  - Correspondence, 1981, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 42-46)
  - Correspondence, 1982, (8 folders) (Box 3, Folder 47-54)
  - Correspondence, 1983, (6 folders; see also Boxes 13-14) (Box 3, Folder 55-60)
  - Correspondence, 1984, (12 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 3, Folder 61-72)
  - Correspondence, 1985, (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence, 1986, (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 8-15)
  - Correspondence, 1987, (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 16-24)
  - Correspondence, 1988, (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 25-32)
  - Correspondence, 1989, (9 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 4, Folder 33-41)
  - Correspondence, 1990, (16 folders) (Box 4, Folder 42-57)
  - Correspondence, 1991, (10 folders) (Box 4, Folder 58-67)
  - Correspondence, 1992, (13 folders) (Box 4, Folder 68-80)
  - Correspondence, 1993, (14 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-14)
  - Correspondence, 1994, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
  - Oversize Letter from Tblisi, May 4, 1963 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Letter from Denise René with Silkscreen Design by Vasarely, 1969 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Two Oversize Easter Cards with Drawings by Hedda Sterne, 1969 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Drawing by Juliet Kepes, Jul 15, 1977 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Drawing by Hedda Sterne, Jul 15, 1979 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Painting by Gyorgy Kepes, Jul 15, 1983 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Drawing by Juliet Kepes, Jul 15, 1983 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Drawing by Juliet Kepes, Jul 15, 1984 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Dawing by Juliet Kepes, Jul 15, 1989 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Christmas Card with Collage by Regina Bogat Jensen, 1979 (Box 14 (sol))
  - Oversize Christmas Card with Collage by Regina Bogat Jensen, 1980 (Box 14 (sol))
  - Oversize Christmas Card with Collage by Regina Bogat Jensen, 1983 (Box 14 (sol))
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Drawing by Juliet Kepes, Jul 15, 1973 (Box OV 15)
  - Oversize Birthday Card with Drawing by Juliet Kepes, Jul 15, 1974 (Box OV 15)